{
  "title": "Computer_Network - Computer_Network — Slot 6 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Computer_Network — Slot 6",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Which media access control protocol is used by IEEE 802.11 wireless LAN? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>CDMA</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>CSMA/CA</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>ALOHA</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>CSMA/CA</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128661/isro2017-32\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following protocol is used for transferring electronic mail messages from one machine to another? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>TELNET</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>FTP</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>SNMP</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>SMTP</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>SMTP</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128659/isro2017-31\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>If there are n devices (nodes) in a network, what is the number of cable links required for a fully connected mesh and a star topology respectively <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>n(n-1)/2 , n-1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>n, n-1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>n-1, n</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>n-1,  n(n-1)/2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>n(n-1)/2 , n-1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128657/isro2017-30\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>The default subnet mask for a class B network can be <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>255.255.255.0</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>255.0.0.0</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>255.255.192.0</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>255.255.0.0</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>255.255.0.0</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128648/isro2017-29\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>In networking terminology UTP means <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Uniquitous teflon port</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Uniformly terminating port</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Unshielded twisted pair</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Unshielded T-connector port</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Unshielded twisted pair</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128646/isro2017-28\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Physical topology of FDDI is? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Bus</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Ring</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Star</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Ring</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128644/isro2017-27\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Consider two hosts X and Y, connected by a single direct link of rate \\(10^{6}\\) bits/sec . The\ndistance between the two hosts is 10,000 km and the propagation speed along the link is\n2x\\(10^{8}\\) m/sec . Host X sends a file of 50,000 bytes as one large message to host Y\ncontinuously. Let the transmission and propagation delays be p milliseconds and q\nmilliseconds, respectively . Then the values of p and q are <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>p = 50 and q = 100</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>p = 50 and q = 400</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>p = 100 and q = 50</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>p = 400 and q = 50</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>p = 400 and q = 50</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118537/gate2017-2-35#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Consider a binary code that consists of only four valid code words as given below:<br>\n00000,01011,10101,11110<br>\nLet the minimum Hamming distance of the code be p and the maximum number of erroneous\nbits that can be corrected by the code be q. Then the values of p and q are <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>p = 3 and q = 1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>p = 3 and q = 2</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>p = 4 and q = 2</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>p = 4 and q = 1</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>p = 3 and q = 1</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118376/gate2017-2-34#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>The maximum number of IPv4 router addresses that can be listed in the record route (RR)\noption field of an IPv4 header is _________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "9",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118427/gate2017-2-20#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Consider socket API on a Linux machine that supports connected UDP sockets. A connected\nUDP socket is a UDP socket on which connect function has already been called. Which of the\nfollowing statements is/are CORRECT ?<br>\nI. A connected UDP socket can be used to communicate with multiple peers\nsimultaneously.<br>\nII. A process can successfully call connect function again for an already connected UDP\nsocket. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>II only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both I and II</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither I nor II</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>II only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118209/gate2017-2-18#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following statements about the routing protocols, Routing Information Protocol\n(RIP) and Open Shortest Path First (OSPF) in an IPv4 network. <br><br>\nI. RIP uses distance vector routing  <br>\nII. RIP packets are sent using UDP  <br>\nIII. OSPF packets are sent using TCP <br>\nIV. OSPF operation is based on link-state routing <br><br>\nWhich of the statements above are CORRECT? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I and IV only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I, II and III only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>I, II and IV only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>II, III and IV only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>I, II and IV only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118338/gate2017-2-9#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>The values of parameters for the Stop-and-Wait ARQ protocol are as given below:<br><br>\nBit rate of the transmission channel = 1Mbps <br>\nPropagation delay from sender to receiver = 0.75 ms <br>\nTime to process a frame = 0.25ms <br>\nNumber of bytes in the information frame =1980 <br>\nNumber of bytes in the acknowledge frame = 20          <br>                               Number of overhead bytes in the information frame = 20 <br><br>\nAssume that there are no transmission errors. Then the transmission efficiency ( expressed in\npercentage) of the Stop-and - Wait ARQ protocol for the above parameters is _________(\ncorrect to 2 decimal places) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "86.5",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118328/gate2017-1-45#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>In a RSA cryptosystem a participant A uses two prime numbers p=13 and q=17 to generate\nher public and private keys. If the public key of A is 35. Then the private key of A is\n__________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "11",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118327/gate2017-1-44#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>A computer network uses polynomials over GF(2) for error checking with 8 bits as\ninformation bits and uses \\(x^{3}+x+1\\) as the generator polynomial to generate the check bits. In\nthis network, the message 01011011 is transmitted as <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>01011011010</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>01011011011</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>01011011101</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>01011011100</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>01011011101</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118313/gate2017-1-32#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>A sender S sends a message m to receiver R, which is digitally signed by S with its\nprivate key. In this scenario, one or more of the following security violations can take place. <br><br>\nI. S can launch a birthday attack to replace m with a fraudulent message.<br>\nII. A third party attacker can launch a birthday attack to replace m with a fraudulent message  <br>  III. R can launch a birthday attack to replace m with a fraudulent message.<br><br>\nWhich of the following are possible security violations? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I and II only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>II only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>II and III only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>I only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118295/gate2017-1-15#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}